新法警呢
The new marshal?
楼上
Upstairs.
该死  博汉南  你不知道
Damn, Bohannon. Don't you know interruptin'
干扰联邦法警办事
a federal marshal while he is conducting business
是违法的吗
is against the law?
从来没把你当警察过
Never figured you for a lawman.
这份工作的确有好处
Yeah, well, job does have its advantages.
我是来要求你释放我的工人的
Come to see my workers released.
你是说你的罪犯吧
Your criminals, you mean.
等早上的火车到达时
You have 'em down at the depot by the time
你就让他们到火车站  好吗
the mornin' train arrives, all right?
怎么  让我的女人孤单一人吗
What, and leave my lady all by her lonesome?
我才不要
I don't think so.
我觉得我在这里就很舒服
I think I'm comfy right here.
该死  博汉南  你太紧张了
Damn, Bohannon. You're all twisted up.
也许你需要好好干一炮
You might could use a good poke.
弗朗辛  不如你过去
Francine, why don't you go over there and see
帮上校泻泻火
if you can help colonel out?
快啊
Come on, now.
我不会告诉你老婆的
I ain't gonna tell the missus.
杜兰特和坎贝尔之间的矛盾
This here fight's between Durant and Campbell.
与你我无关
Got nothin' to do with you and me.
这警徽表示我为坎贝尔效力
Well, this here badge says I work for Campbell.
据我所知  你为杜兰特工作
Last I heard, you work for Durant,
所以这就说明咱俩之间也有矛盾  你说呢
so reckon that makes this here fight 'tween us, don't you?
你在为投机分子工作
You're workin' for a carpetbagger.
如今这种日子里  谁给我钱我就效忠谁
My loyalty runs the length of a dollar bill these days.
放了我手下
Let go of my men.
如果我不放呢
Let's say I don't.
如果你是来杀我的  那我早死了
If you'd come to kill me, I'd be dead already.
十点  放我的人去火车站
My men, at the depot, 10:00 a.m.
你真是发神经了
You done lost your nerve.
这下是因为你拿枪对着我妻儿
That's for putting a gun on my wife and boy.
下次我不会敲门了
Next time I won't knock.
花了那么多天建造  又花了两周挖那个斜坡
Days to build, two weeks to dig the grade.
一个月后我们就能过谢尔曼峰  七月能到拉勒米
We'll be over Sherman Peak in a month, Laramie by July.
它又不会自己造好
It won't build itself.
会有人造啊
Men'll build it.
技术工人都被关起来了
All the skilled men are locked up
都是因为你那个朋友西德尼·斯诺
thanks to your friend Sidney Snow.
他交给我对付就行
You let me worry about him.
不管你在想什么  博汉南  不要
Whatever you're thinkin', Bohannon, don't.
我们和斯诺最好别互相干涉
Leave Snow to his job, us to ours.
新任法警让我捎个口信给你
Got a message for you from the new marshal.
说吧  德国佬
Spit it out, Dutch.
他说  "想要你的人"
He said, "You want the men?
"就自己来领"
Come and get 'em."
《先驱报》
新任法警为知名杀人犯
你看报纸没  博汉南
You see this, Bohannon?
"新任法警为知名杀人犯"
"Known killer hired as marshal."
这个世界怎么了
I mean, what is the world comin' to?
我给你机会让你轻轻松松放了他们的
I gave you a chance to let go of them men easy-like.
我也给你机会让你自己动手放人
Then I gave you a chance to let 'em out yourself.
随时欢迎回来
Come on back anytime!
早上好
Good mornin'.
一点都不好
No, it ain't.
德国佬  自己滚回牢房
Dutch, get your ass back in there.
如果博汉南先生今天想...
If Mr. Bohannon should get any ideas...
-做一点出格的事...  -要逮捕他吗
- step a hair out of line today... - Arrest him?
直接杀了他
Shoot him.
到时间了啊
Well, it's about time.
杜兰特先生  时间啊
Time, Mr. Durant,
就是个善变的情妇
is a fickle mistress.
最开始它好像无穷无尽让你享受
First it appears an endless supply,
可是突然之间  沙漏里最后几粒沙
and then suddenly the last few grains of sand
就漏尽了
trickle down the hourglass.
天哪  约翰
For God's sake, John.
用莫须有的罪名迫害我无异于政治自杀
Persecuting me on trumped-up charges is political suicide.
你根本没有证据
You have no evidence
证明我跟海柯德法警的死有关
that I had anything to do with Marshal Heckard's death.
你没有人证  也没有物证
You've no witness. No proof.
这得奥马哈的法官说了算
That's for the judge in Omaha to determine.
奥马哈吗
Omaha?
你们都会被遣返回
All of you will be returned to the jurisdictions
你们犯下被指控罪名的司法辖区
in which your alleged crimes were committed.
在那里服刑  无论好坏
You will acquit yourself there for better or worse.
我不能回阿拉巴马  坎贝尔先生
I can't go back to Alabama, Mr. Campbell.
你得感谢杜兰特先生  这是拜他所赐
You have Mr. Durant to thank for that.
火车今天就走
The train leaves today.
你不会是来真的吧
You can't be serious!
我会...
Oh, I can...
而且就是
and I am.
借你的牧场工人一用  玛吉
I need your ranchers, Maggie.
我自己没法对付坎贝尔
Can't fight Campbell on my own.
我丈夫在这里还是
My husband built up a small ranch out here
一片荒芜的时候
when there was nothin' but rollin' hills
建起一座小牧场
as far as the eye could see.
-我们有栋小房子  一小群牛  -我来
- We had a house, small herd. - Come on.
按住它
Steady him.
而在58年的九月初  我们的一个手下
and in early September '58, one of our hands--
一个窘迫的牛仔  叫杰克什么的
a down on his luck cowpoke, a Jack somebody--
领来了一群偷牛贼
he led a bunch of rustlers.
毁了我们的牛群
Tore through our herd.
那晚我丈夫去世了
Lost my husband that night.
一个月后牧场也没了
Ranch a month later.
我得从头新建  也做到了
I had to rebuild it all, and I did...
流过血汗  拼尽了一切
with blood, sweat, and whatever else it took.
西德尼·斯诺  他是坎贝尔在镇上的亲信
Sidney Snow, he's Campbell's brand on this town.
跟他作对只会引起更多流血事件
Fighting him is only gonna lead to more bloodshed.
总得有人站出来
Somebody's got to take a stand.
这跟我丈夫被杰克杀死前
That's exactly what my husband said
说的一模一样
Just before Jack killed him.
坎贝尔不会罢休  卡伦  你明白
Campbell won't let go, Cullen. You know that.
我去山北了
I'm off to the north valley.
那里不是米奇·麦克吉尼斯的地吗
Thought that was Mickey McGinnes's land?
昨天贱卖给我了
Sold it to me yesterday for 10 cents on the dollar.
你是说昨天吗
Y-you said this is yesterday?
注意安全  博汉南先生
Hold on to your topknot, Mr. Bohannon.
坎贝尔刚要了一列火车
Campbell just requisitioned a train.
他要把工人们送回东部
He's sending the workers back east.
博汉南
Bohannon...
你明白这是什么意思吗
you know what this means?
意思是我时间不多了
Means I got less time than I thought.
我以为你是那个新法警呢
Thought you were the new marshal.
我以为你跑路了
Thought you turned tail and run.
我是带着计划回来的
Come back with a plan, I did.
我的人已经在路上了
I got men coming.
随时都可能到
Any day now.
坎贝尔要把杜兰特和工人们运回东部
Campbell's shippin' Durant and the men back east.
我才不在乎杜兰特那叛徒会怎么样
I don't care what happens to that Judas Durant.
这是他自找的
He deserves what he's got coming.
其他人是无辜的
The men don't.
我不在乎你的铁路  博汉南
I don't care about your railroad, Bohannon.
我有私仇要报
I've got me own travails.
我的人一到
When my men arrive,
我就亲自收拾那个混蛋坎贝尔  好吗
I'll take care of these Campbell bastards meself, all right?
你这样做只会让自己走上绞刑架
You're likely to find yourself on the wrong end of a rope.
这不关你的事
That's no business of yours.
你应该带上老婆离开这里
You should take your wife and move on from here.
我老婆和孩子回史密斯保卫站了
My wife and child are back at Fort Smith.
铁路需要继续向前铺
It's the railroad needs movin' now.
坎贝尔不会交出工人的
Campbell's not just gonna hand over these workers.
我们得劫狱
We're gonna break 'em out.
就今天
Today.
你和我吗
You and me?
两个人对付那么多人吗
Two men against all them?
他们都听命于西德尼·斯诺
All them amounts to one man: Sidney Snow.
这有可能是在自杀
It could be suicide.
不能什么都不做  迈克
Doing nothing ain't a choice, Mick.
他们多数人都是酒鬼和流氓
Most of them are drunkards and shitpokes.
枪一响  一半的人都会缩回去
Half will fold if the bullets start flying.
我去对付西德尼
And I'll take care of Sidney.
午饭好了  去洗手吧
Wash up for lunch?
我们需要枪  很多枪
We'll need guns, and lots of 'em.
他们多数人都想不到会被袭击  也没准备
Most of 'em won't be expecting a fight nor ready for one.
出其不意比子弹更有效
Surprise is better than bullets.
我同意要出其不意
I'll take the surprise,
但我也要子弹
but I'll be having me bullets as well.
你们应该为自己感到羞耻
You should be ashamed of yourselves.
竟然在谈枪啊子弹啊什么的
All this talk of guns and bullets?
我们不会再给你和以斯拉再添麻烦了
We won't trouble you and Ezra much longer.
谢谢
Thank you.
感谢你让我避难  露丝
Appreciate the sanctuary, Ruth.
他是个恶魔  你知道的
He's evil, you know.
米奇吗
Mickey?
那个新法警  西德尼·斯诺
That new marshal, Sidney Snow.
战后许多人都迷失了方向
Lot of men lost their way after the war.
他并没有迷失  博汉南先生
He's not lost, Mr. Bohannon.
黑暗的力量驻留在他心中
The forces of darkness reside within him.
我望进他的双眼
I looked into his eyes.
在其中看见了尚未被释放的恶
I saw a wickedness there that is yet to be unleashed.
小心一点
Be careful.
这儿还是有人关心你的
There are still people here who care for you.
你信上帝吗  博汉南
You believe in God, Bohannon?
耶稣之类的屁话
Jesus and all that shit?
我向来不理解人们向一个
I never understood people prayin' to a guy
让自己被钉上十字架的人祈祷
who let himself get crucified.
为了什么呢
And for what?
我认为对某些人解释信仰还真不太容易
I reckon faith ain't easily explained to some.
你瞧  我站在这儿  看着
See, I stand here and I look,
我看见了卡伦·博汉南
and I see Cullen Bohannon,
但是我已经认不出他了
but I sure as hell don't recognize him.
监狱  上车车站  或者第一个加水站
The jail, the load-up, or the first water stop.
你准备袭击哪里
Which it gonna be?
我知道你在谋划着什么
I know you're planning something.
我在忙铁路上的事儿
Railroad work.
拜托  在主的殿宇外面撒谎
Come on, now. Lying just outside the house of the lord?
假如你这么确信我在撒谎  何不逮捕我
If you're so sure I'm lying, why don't you arrest me?
他妈的我才不想把所有的乐趣都毁掉呢
Well, shit, I don't want to ruin all the fun.
你现在抽身还不算晚
Ain't too late to walk away.
不  已经太晚了...
Yeah, it is...
对我俩而言都太晚了
For both of us.
那最好自祈多福吧
Best pray on it then.
以防万一
Just to be safe.
还是你去祈祷好了
Oh, I leave the prayin' to you.
你需要运气
You gonna need it.
我和坎贝尔没仇
I got no feud with Campbell.
他逮捕了你的工人
He arrested your workers!
还有你的老板
And your boss.
杜兰特是自掘坟墓
Durant dug his own grave,
在我看来他迟早出事儿
as I knew he would sooner or later.
没有他  铁路是修不起来的
Road won't get built without him.
和州长干仗就算是造反了  博汉南先生
Going to war with the governor is insurrection, Mr. Bohannon.
这不是我第一次这么做了
Wouldn't be my first do-si-do.
你会被抓进监狱的  或者更糟
You'll wind up in prison or worse.
是啊  我也不是第一次进监狱了
Yeah, danced that number likewise.
你在找什么呢
What are you lookin' for?
找那该死的武器库的钥匙
Lookin' for the keys to the damn armory...
还有一位搭档
And a partner.
博汉南先生  我是工程师  不是枪手
Mr. Bohannon, I'm an engineer, not a gunslinger.
你为联太公司工作  德莱尼先生
You work for the Union Pacific, Mr. Delaney.
对有些人来说这是梦想
That's a dream for some.
对另一些人来说  这是一种痴迷
For others, it's an obsession.
我的祖父白手起家在沼泽地上
My granddaddy tore hisself a cotton empire
建起了一个棉花王国
out of swamp bottom and a sun,
我的目标是在这条铁路上做出类似的事
and I aim to do similar with this here railroad.
所以你要么就给我钥匙
So you either give me them keys...
要么就别挡我的道
or you get out of my way.
好的
All right then.
你有计划吧
You got a plan...
但愿
I hope.
很好  谢谢你
That's great. Thank you.
你让我刮目相看  埃里森小姐
You surprise me, Miss Ellison.
一顿大餐和一杯红酒
A nice dinner and a glass of wine
改变不了真相  坎贝尔先生
don't change the truth, Mr. Campbell.
我倒也没指望
Nor would I expect them to.
我只是没想到你会在你的文章里
I just didn't expect you to lend any credence in your article
帮博汉南先生说话而不帮我
to my position over that of Mr. Bohannon's.
博汉南先生是非分明
Mr. Bohannon sees the world in black and white.
但我们不是  对吧
But we don't, do we?
你和我有很多共同之处  坎贝尔先生
I suspect what you and I have in common, Mr. Campbell...
其中之一就是
among other things...
认为这个世界不是黑白分明的
is the certainty that the world is neither black nor white
而是灰色的
but decidedly gray.
所以这个世界既令人沮丧
That's what makes it both daunting and,
但同时又很诱人
at times, alluring.
更不用说还有惊喜了
Not to mention surprising.
或许我们在帕默餐馆共进午餐
Perhaps it wouldn't be intolerable
一起聊聊这个
to discuss a world,
灰色的世界
in all its shade of gray,
不是不可接受的事
over lunch at the Palmer?
完全可以接受  坎贝尔先生
That wouldn't be intolerable at all, Mr. Campbell.
猎枪  带子弹和火药
Shotgun. Balls and powder.
全部都要
All of 'em.
枪架上所有的
The whole rack?
所有的
All of it.
我这里不能赊账的
I ain't trading on credit.
我也不赊账  那上面的也要
Neither am I. On the hop.
这镇上没有秘密的  麦克吉尼斯
Ain't no secrets in this town, McGinnes.
这点你早该明白
You ought to know that by now.
哎呦
Damn.
瞧瞧  博汉南
Lookee here, Bohannon.
我又抓了一个哦
Caught me another one.
我知道你买那些枪可不是用来打鱼的
Now, I know them shotguns wasn't just for shootin' fish.
我看你是没挨够打吧
I guess you just ain't had enough yet.
这话倒是说对了
You got that right.
住手
Stop it!
他显然什么也不知道  否则他早招了
He obviously knows nothing or he would have told you by now!
你要是再啰嗦  下一个就是你  软柿子
Yeah, you keep squawkin', you'll be next, huckleberry.
我知道博汉南打算救他们出去
Now, I know Bohannon is planning on busting these men out...
我知道你也参与了
and I know that you are a part of it.
说吧
So...
他为什么不理我  派克
Why won't he talk to me, Parker?
不知道  西德
I don't know, Sid.
也许是因为他讨厌你吧
Maybe he don't like you.
讨厌我
Doesn't like me?
把他扶起来
Go ahead, get him up.
不  别再打了
Don't! No more!
别再打了
No more.
够了
That's enough.
他要救他们出去
He's gonna bust the men out.
这我本来就知道
Yeah, I know that.
在哪救
Where?
监狱  上车车站
The jail? The load-up?
还是第一个加水站
The first water stop?
上车车站
The load-up.
在空旷地带  很聪明
Get us out in the open. That's smart.
还有呢
What else?
我就知道这么多
It's all I know.
我发誓
I swear.
锁起来
Lock him up.
准备装犯人上车
Prep the prisoners for load-up.
还有两个小时才走呢
We ain't leavin' for two hours.
要随机应变  艾特伍德
Adapt or die, Atwood.
随机应变
Adapt or die.
我们还得检查一遍镇子呢
We still need to sweep the town.
我们没时间了
We ain't got time...
不过博汉南也没有了
and neither does Bohannon.
你跟爱尔兰小鸟似的全招了
You sang like a Irish canary.
你们谁又能像他一样
I challenge any man here
承受这样的拷问还不招供的
to endure a beating like that and keep his mouth shut.
博汉南是我们逃出去的唯一机会
Bohannon was our last chance to get out of here.
我要是回阿拉巴马  就是个死人了
I go back to Alabama, I'm a dead man...
但你也别想好过
But you ain't gonna make it out this--
冷静点
Easy!
别碰他
Leave him be!
他会遭到报应的
He gonna get what comin' to him!
那也不需要你这种人来动手
Not from the likes of you, he won't!
先生们  别这样
Gentlemen, please!
自己人起内讧...
Fighting amongst oursel--
闭嘴  胖子
Quiet, fat man!
都是因为你  我们才会困在这
It's 'cause of you we in here.
有什么想狡辩的吗  爱尔兰佬
Got to say for yourself, Irish?
清者自清  对吧
Speaks for itself, don't it?
他在哪
Where is he?
你一直把他藏起来是吧
You been hidin' him, ain't you?
他不在这
He's not here.
是啊  可是他之前在这对吧
Yeah, but he was here, wasn't he?
他跟那个满口胡话的爱尔兰鬼佬
Him and that lyin' shit-ass Irishman.
我什么都没干
I've done nothing.
我这什么都没有
I have nothing for you.
别玩火  教堂妞
Don't be playin' with fire, church lady.
好了  把他们带出来
All right, bring 'em out.
博汉南呢
Bohannon?
保持警惕  先生们
Stay awake, gentlemen.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
想到你以前的种种
Considering your past...
浪漫的嗜好
romantic predilections.
你一直对我很好奇
You have been curious about me.
是啊  我打听过你的消息
Oh, I've made inquiries.
我年轻的时候  我以为那意味着我不正常
When I was younger, I used to think it made me abnormal.
但是经历过战争后
But after my time covering the war,
我发现男人也是一样
I realized that there were men who were equally as...
迷惑吗
Confused?
是好奇
Curious.
你想要什么  约翰·坎贝尔
What do you want, John Campbell?
从你身上吗
From you?
从生活中
From life.
有一天
One day...
我希望能得到我应得的东西
when I get what I deserve...
不用靠厮杀
without a fight...
不留下遗憾
and without regret.
那可能吗
Is that even possible?
目前来看  不可能
So far...No.
坎贝尔先生
Mr. Campbell.
我是西德尼·斯诺
Sidney Snow.
州长先生
Mr. Governor, sir.
拜托
Come on.
有屁快放
Be quick.
我需要您发电报到朱尔斯堡  让他们把所有
I need you to wire Julesburg for all the deputies
空闲的警官派过来
they can spare.
到肯莫尔的沃特车站见我
Have 'em meet me at the water stop at Kenmore.
-因为博汉南吗  -对
- Bohannon? - Yeah.
不要再让我听到卡伦·博汉南这个名字
I never want to hear the name Cullen Bohannon again.
好了  让他们上车
All right, load 'em up.
你们都给我严肃点
Y'all get your minds right.
我说结束才能放松
This ain't over till I say it is.
我不喜欢你看我的眼神
I don't like the way you're lookin' at me.
什么眼神
Lookin' at what?
你听不懂吗
You hear what I said?
你个狗娘养的傻缺
You ignorant son of a bitch.
你要为此付出代价
That's gonna cost ya.
不
No!
把其他人的手铐也打开
Free the rest of them men.
-看着这俩守卫  -谢谢  博汉南
- Watch over them guards. - Thank you, Bohannon.
伙计们  快动手
Aye, lads. Here's the business.
快帮我们打开
Unlock us.
-怎么了  -该死
- What's the matter? - Shit!
我跟你们说过了别放松警惕
I told you this wasn't over.
快让火车停下  快去
Stop the train! Now!
我们得回去
We're goin' back.
算你厉害  博汉南
All right, Bohannon.
如果他们跟着我们一起回了夏安镇
If we return to Cheyenne with them on our tail,
就跟一开始没两样
we'll be right back where we started.
但你自由了不是吗
Free, ain't ya?
只是暂时的
For the moment.
他们那帮人可能会为坎贝尔卖命
Them men might fight for Campbell's cause,
但肯定不会为西德尼去死的
but they sure as hell won't die for Sidney.
你凭什么这么肯定
What makes you so sure?
就凭我们比他们人多
For one thing, they're outmanned.
-但是武器比我们多  -现在不是了
- And we're outgunned. - Not anymore.
不干一仗他是不会罢休的
He's not going to give up without a fight.
我不会杀西德尼的
Yeah, I won't kill Sidney...
但我会抓他进监狱
but I will bring him in.
我们回夏安镇以后
Now, when we get back to Cheyenne,
你要跟坎贝尔讲和
You make things right with Campbell.
他想保住工作
He wants to keep his job.
他只和你谈判
He'll negotiate with you.
你的自信很烦人  博汉南
Your confidence is very annoying, Bohannon.
如果是你  我想你也会做同样的事
I was just ponderin' what you'd do if things was similar.
如果我想错了  你可以直说
I'm wrong, you tell me now.
跟当年一样啊
Just like old times.
当他们开枪打你时
I preferred the cover of the hotel...
我更喜欢躲在宾馆里面
when they were shooting at you.
西德尼
Sidney!
这行为可不绅士  博汉南
That weren't real gentleman-like, Bohannon...
像这样劫走我的囚犯
Stealin' all my prisoners like that.
你不该把钥匙给我的  孩子
Never should have given me them keys, son.
我需要你归还那些囚犯
I'ma need those prisoners back.
这些囚犯是自由人  而且有武器
Them prisoners is liberated, and armed.
-这次你赢不了  -是吗
- Can't win this one. - Oh, yeah?
我又不是来和你赌博的  博汉南
I ain't gonna parlay with you, Bohannon.
看来我们只能靠武力解决了
I reckon we gonna have to shoot it out.
对  你也可以投降
Yeah, you could always give yourself up.
你怎么不过来投降
Ah. Why don't you come on over here and give yourself up?
果然不出所料
That's what I thought.
你只能亲自过来抓我了
Just gonna have to come get me, I guess.
德莱尼
Delaney!
最后一次机会  西德  结束了
Last chance, Sid. End of the line.
压制住他们  伙计们
Keep 'em pinned, boys!
德莱尼  见鬼  德莱尼
Delaney! Damn it, Delaney!
快动手
Do it now!
停火
Hold your fire!
停火  够了
Hold! Enough!
够了  停火
Enough! Hold it!
该死  德莱尼  给我停火
Damn it, Delaney! Hold your damn fire!
借过
Pardon me.
西德尼
Sidney!
西德尼·斯诺
Sidney Snow!
他去哪了
Where'd he go?
那个混蛋在哪
Where is that bastard?
他跑了
Gone.
不  他没有
No, he ain't.